



VICTORIA BIAN

PRODUCT DESIGNER & FRONT-END DEVELOPER

I'm a 21 year-old product designer based in Berkeley, CA. I think about the bigger picture to solve a problem. I combine the iterative brainstorming process with the pixel perfect craftsmanship to create a solution that solves people's needs. I am currently available for freelance design projects.

EDUCATION

UC BERKELEY

Cognitive Science
Minor in Computer Science
Class of 2017 (Graduating early in Dec 2016)

EXPERIENCE

ETSY

Product Design Intern

June 2016 - August 2016

GRADESCOPE

User Interface Intern, Design Consultant April 2015 - August 2015

FREELANCE

Product Designer

March 2015 - Current

WAYGO APP

User Experience Designer September 2015 - December 2015 **SKILLS**

UI/UX Design: Sketch 3 Photoshop Usability Testing Storyboarding

User Research Wireframing Prototyping

Web Development: HTML5 CSS3 JavaScript JQuery Ruby on Rails

Programming: Python Java Swift

Personal: French Typography Photography

As a product design intern, I worked closely with our team on designing and coding a delightful experience for sellers and buyers. During my internship, I learned more about design systems and user research. I can't really share what I've worked on but I've posted my thoughts and lessons on my portfolio.

Interned at Gradescope, an educational startup based in Berkeley that focuses on making online grading efficient for instructors and providing users with insightful feedbacks on assignments and tests. Worked on multiple UI improvements and designed for upcoming features such as Assignment Stats, Autograder, etc.

Worked on freelance apps for clients and designed for ideas we came up with on our own. Recently worked on FOSSA, a dev tool for product managers and developers that streamlines the process of tracking and fixing issues related to licenses in code. Redesigned workflow for FOSSA features and crafted their brand identity.

Collaborated with members at Berkeley Innovation to transform the translation experience on iPhone and Google Glass. Waygo is an app that turns your iPhone camera into an instant translator for Asian languages and works on wearables such as Google Glass. Improved the app interface and brainstormed features on wearables.